[female voice]
We have apprehended
a dangerous threat
in one of our very own labs.
- [crowd gasping]
- Quiet!
We believe that this...
this monstrosity...
- [snoring]
- [crowd gasping]
...is the product of illegal
genetic experimentation.
What deranged lunatic would
create something like this?
[alien grunts, clears throat]
I prefer "deranged genius,"
but thank you
for the introduction.
Dr. Jumba Jookiba,
you were tasked
with safely studying
biological threats,
not creating them.
A threat?
- Experiment 626...
- [glass clanging]
...is our federation's
most sophisticated weapon.
- [growling]
- [crowd gasping]
626 is unstoppable.
Indestructible.
[laughs]
And smarter
than 100 supercomputers.
- [speaking Tantalog]
- I don't wanna play anymore!
It's an atrocity!
- Destroy it!
- I can't even look at him.
He should be exiled.
[leader] Silence!
He did not ask to be created.
Perhaps, if he is
so intelligent,
he has the capacity to reason.
Experiment 626, show us
that there is something
inside you
that is good.
[speaking Tantalog]
[clears throat]
[crowd gasping]
So naughty.
Throwing up. Throwing up.
I did not teach him that.
You have made
our decision easy.
He is clearly the flawed
product of a deranged mind.
Dr. Jookiba,
your lab will be destroyed.
Okay. Just leave me 626.
And 626 exiled.
Oh, come on!
- Bailiff.
- Wait.
No, no, no, no!
You can't do that.
No!
[grunts] Huh?
- [gasps]
- Don't get any ideas.
These guns are locked on
your genetic signature.
They're not gonna shoot anyone
but you.
[laughs]
Hmm. Oh.
Knock it off! Federation
strictly forbids being gross.
Don't make me say it-- Ew!
[guns charging up]
Uh-oh.
- [alarms blaring]
- [leader] Where is he?
He's loose on Deck C.
[officer]
Now heading for the hull.
What?
He's trying
to find the police...
[laughs, blows raspberry,
chuckles]
...cruisers.
He, uh... He took the red one.
Fire at will!
[cackles]
He's in hyperspace.
Where will he exit?
In 12 hours,
we project he will collide
with a planet called "E-arth."
That's a planet full of water.
Water increases
his molecular density.
[aliens] Uh...
He'll become heavy and drown.
Oh!
So I think we can all say
farewell to 62...
You're kidding.
- [alarms blaring]
- [all sighing]
Oh, what a pickle
we've got here! [chuckles]
If only there was
a brilliant genius around
to help you catch
that monster.
You! You're the reason
we're in this mess.
And I could get you out of it.
If you release me
and give me back my lab.
Nonsense. We'll simply
vaporize the planet. Captain.
Armed and ready,
Councilwoman.
Hold it! Hold everything!
Excuse me. Sorry.
Excuse me. Pardon me.
You can't destroy the planet!
Aw, man.
Uh, who's this?
Agent Pleakley.
Earth expert at your service.
Howdy.
"Earth expert"?
I'm an expert in that planet's
flora, fauna and fashion.
Yeah, this outfit
screams "expert."
Yeah. I'm researching
an Earth species
that's half-cow and half-boy.
- It's quite fascinating--
- Yes, marvelous.
What's your point?
Oh, uh, Earth is
a protected wildlife reserve.
We've been using it to rebuild
the mosquito population.
[sighs] Crikey. Very well.
Dr. Jookiba, you will travel
to Earth, where you will
capture the escaped
lab experiment known as 626.
Agent Pleakley,
you will be going with him.
You are deputized to ensure
he follows Federation rules.
What?
I don't need a babysitter.
This is all very dangerous,
and it's likely you'll die.
Do you accept?
[breathes heavily]
With every heart in my body,
of course I accept!
I'm going to Earth!
Hey, everyone!
- If I may...
- Thank you, thank you.
- Can I hug you?
- No.
- Can I hug--
Sorry. Permission to hug
the Grand Councilwoman?
- That's not going to happen.
- Of course. My apologies.
I do not need supervision.
You have asked...
Permission to hug
my new partner?
Brilliant. Permission granted.
So what I'm just trying
to say is, I--
It would just be better
if I went by myself.
Do not let the Earthlings
discover your mission,
or I will be forced
to intervene.
This is a dream vacay.
[gasps]
I have so much packing to do!
Well, well, well, 626.
What hideous, pathetic planet
is caught in your crosshairs?
[♪ "He Mele No Lilo" playing]
[breathing through mask]
Let's go snorkeling later.
Yeah, that's a great idea.
I know, right? So cool.
They have the best sandwiches.
Are you supposed to be here?
I'm in town
for the convention.
Cool.
You're free! Go, go!
Live your lives!
No, no, no! No! Lilo.
Not again.
They deserve to be free!
Lilo!
I'm gonna have to talk
to Nani about this.
[watch alarm beeping]
[screams] Sorry!
Sorry, sorry. Sorry.
[phone ringing]
Hey, Jimmy's Luau.
Hey, brother.
- Go, go. Hurry.
- Sorry.
Hey. You're gonna be late.
Yeah.
[dancer] Where is she?
She's always late.
[teacher]
Has anyone seen Lilo?
Lilo, thank goodness.
I thought you were gonna
be on time today.
I had to get a sandwich
for Pudge.
Is Pudge a friend in need?
He's a fish.
I forgot to tell you that.
So, you're late because
you fed a sandwich to a fish?
Yeah.
Pudge controls the weather.
[chuckles] She's so weird.
Lilo, honey, come on.
Get dressed, honey.
Oh, guys, look.
I got
a friendship bracelet too.
[dancer] That's not
a friendship bracelet.
Ew, garbage girl
puts garbage on her arm.
Girls, hāmau. Hoʻomākaukau.
Come on.
You know, silly,
it's not a friendship bracelet
if you don't have any friends.
Girls, girls, girls.
Hui! Kulikuli.
Stand in line. Get ready.
[engine sputters]
No, no, no.
Okay, not today.
She's not coming.
[audience murmuring]
- [dancer screams]
- [audience clamoring]
- Kumu!
- [attendee] Who's her parents?
Girls, go.
[attendee 1]
She acts up all the time.
[attendee 2] Somebody
needs to look after her.
She's always causing trouble.
[attendee 1]
She's just not a good fit.
Kumu, where is her sister?
That's the real question here.
[teacher] It's a delicate
home situation for Lilo.
She's not a bad kid.
She just needs--
[attendee 1]
I don't know, Kumu.
I just don't know.
[attendee 2]
She disrupts the class
and ruined
today's performance.
♪ Well, since my baby left me ♪
♪ Well, I've found a new place
To dwell ♪
♪ Well, it's down at the end
Of Lonely Street ♪
[muffled]
♪ At Heartbreak Hotel ♪
♪ I'll be so lonely, baby ♪
♪ I'll be so lonely... ♪
Lilo? Can you please
open the door?
Read the note!
[groans]
I'm sorry I missed
your performance.
- Pāpā's truck died.
- Blah, blah. Wow!
That must be
so stressful for you.
How about you just
leave me alone to die?
No, no, no. Not now, not now.
[horn honks]
The social worker is here.
You can pout later, Lilo.
That's not how pouting works.
[Nani] Lilo, open the door.
I can't hear you.
It's really weird.
Open the door
or I'm breaking it down!
Hey, what is wrong with you?
- [clears throat]
- Uh...
Mrs. Kekoa.
Hi. Um, nice to see you.
Can I, uh, help you
carry anything in?
I'm okay. [chuckles]
Can I help you
carry anything in?
Oh, yeah. Would you mind
if we just, um,
just use the back?
It's just, uh, just right--
We're in the back.
[grunts]
[chuckles]
These old houses, right?
You just gotta have the...
the touch!
Oh! Oh...
There we go! Um... Actually,
would you mind waiting here
for just a second?
- Yes, of course.
- Okay.
- Hey! Don't touch that.
- No, I don't wanna hear it.
- That's mine.
- I'm turning it off right now.
[music stops]
So, uh, what can I
get you to drink?
Do you have tea?
Course I have...
There's a lot
of unpaid bills here, Nani.
[groans]
How often would you say
you leave your little sister
home alone?
What? No. I... No.
Why would I do that? I...
I would never leave
my sister alone. [chuckles]
[Mrs. Kekoa] Smoke, Nani!
- Oh! Oh, uh...
- The alarm! The smoke alarm!
Oh, don't worry.
There's no batteries in there.
Lilo! [chuckles]
I took 'em out
because it kept going off.
[chuckles] That's not true.
Say aloha to Mrs. Kekoa.
Aloha, Lilo. How are you?
Is that blood?
Oh, yeah, I've been practicing
jumping out of my window.
Ha! She's... She's kidding.
She's actually been
very well behaved recently.
Haven't you, right?
[gasps]
Yeah,
I've been more than good,
Mrs. Kekoa.
I've been doing very,
very great at hula.
Made a ton
of new friends there,
and they all think
I'm the coolest.
I've been eating
a lot of organic stuff.
Sometimes I eat too much.
And I've been eating
five or ten times a day.
Sometimes I eat so much, I...
can't...
- breathe.
- [laughs]
That's enough imagination
for you, you little weirdie.
- [microwave dings]
- Oh, tea's ready.
Hmm. Okay, pretty sweet.
Okay, Nani, we both know
this didn't go well today.
I can see you're trying,
but you're too smart for me
to beat around the bush here.
I know it hasn't
been that long
since your parents
passed away,
but my job is to make sure
that Lilo is in
a stable environment.
And I can't say that
in good conscience right now.
Listen, I know this is a lot.
You're practically
a kid yourself.
[māmā] What happened
to knocking?
[Lilo and Nani] We decided
it was a surf day!
- [family cheering, laughing]
- [māmā] A surf day?
Look, you seem like
a goal-oriented person.
We have a new director coming
into town next week,
and I would really,
really love to tell him
that you girls
have turned the corner.
So, why don't we come up with
some goals to achieve by then?
Yeah, yeah.
All right, here.
Three things.
First, I want this house
cleaned, including laundry,
- and a fully-stocked fridge.
- Perfect.
Second, pay all those bills
I saw in the kitchen.
Yes.
And third,
file for health insurance
for you and Lilo.
Got it.
If you do those three things
by Friday,
I might be able
to give you some more time.
Thank you.
Okay.
It was Capri Sun, yeah?
- Yeah.
- I figured.
[Mrs. Kekoa] And
don't forget the insurance.
[Nani chuckles]
Yeah, yeah. You got it.
You're gonna need
that health insurance
for when I kill you!
[screaming]
[Nani growls]
Oh, yeah.
We took out
the smoke alarm batteries.
I'll show you "can't breathe."
Come here!
- [screams] Let go of me!
- Yeah, no.
Ow. Okay.
No, no, no.
Why didn't you wait at hula?
Because you weren't there.
Do you want them
to split us up?
Because that's what's
gonna happen
if we don't get it together.
Hey! Did you just lick me?
Stop pretending you're my mom.
Oh. At least I don't tell
the social worker
I like jumping out of windows.
It's better
than listening to you.
Go to your room!
I'm already in my room!
- [muffled screams]
- [screams]
[goat screams]
Hey, Alvin.
[Nani groans]
[ATV engine revs up]
There she is, Miss Aloha.
Yeah, not today she's not.
Meeting never go well.
I never liked
that government lady anyway.
Why is she always so smiley?
Give me the creeps.
Yeah, well,
our future is in her hands.
Ah, ah. None of that.
Your future is in your hands.
And you're gonna have
a very bright future
'cause of that
akamai brain of yours.
What?
Your acceptance letter
to your dream school
magically taken
out of your trash
and appearing in your bag
at your place of work?
Ooh, that's a sign, girl.
Will you stop with this?
That school is the best school
in the whole world
for that bionic magnets.
Bio... Marine biology.
Marine biology.
And they already
let you in once,
and they wanted
to give you for full ride.
Yeah, I know, but, Tūtū,
there's no way.
Lilo needs me here.
You ever ask Lilo
what she wants?
She's six, so, no.
Sorry, Tūtū.
Had to catch a few extra ones.
The swell was... Hey, Nani!
What are you doing here?
[Nani] I live here.
We're neighbors.
[chuckles] Yeah. Yeah,
that's... that's good. Uh...
The waves were crazy today.
You know, I was like,
"Nani should be here,"
'cause you're always, like,
shredding waves,
and I miss shredding you.
I mean, I miss...
I miss seeing you
shred waves, so...
Yeah.
I've always loved
watching you.
- Not to say that--
- Well said, David.
- Well.
- [David] So, like, when...
when are you gonna go surfing?
[Nani]
Maybe when Lilo turns 18.
Enjoy the surf.
Bebeh.
Now, make up
with your sister, yeah?
You need anything,
you just ask, okay?
We're not just neighbors,
you know.
We're ʻohana.
[ATV engine revs up]
- Yeah, I mean, if you want--
- No, no!
No, David, you've said enough.
[speaking indistinctly]
[space ship rumbling]
- [alarm beeping]
- [computer] Warning.
- Check engine.
- Hmm? [grunts]
[beeping stops]
- [alarm beeping]
- Warning. Check engine.
[beeping stops]
- [computer] Warning. Guidan--
- [grunting]
[chuckles, sighs]
- [alarms blaring]
- Guidance not functional.
Warning. Guidance not
functional. Warning.
Warning.
Guidance not functional.
Crash imminent.
Prepare for impact.
[speaking Tantalog]
[screams]
[knocking on door]
Hey. Think I might've nailed
those kalua sliders you like.
Here.
[groans]
You don't have to eat it.
Nani, am I bad?
What?
That's what everyone says.
Nobody says that.
Maybe some teachers
and school security guards.
Look, you're not bad.
You just do
bad things sometimes.
Just like me earlier,
when I yelled at you.
We just have to learn
from our mistakes.
I shoved Mertle Edmonds today.
I know.
You wanna tell me
what happened?
People treat me different.
[sighs] Baby, they just...
They just don't know
what to say.
But you...
you didn't mean what you said,
did you?
No. Of course not.
You're my sister.
And I'll always be here
for you. Okay?
You got that?
No more tickle town.
Yes, tickle town.
- Tickle town!
- I don't wanna go!
[Lilo] Will you still
be able to visit
when you join the Marines?
[Nani chuckles]
It's not the Marines.
It's marine biology.
Anyway, it's not
gonna happen anymore.
I'm staying right here.
Remember when we put up
those constellations?
[Nani] The Three Sisters.
That one's you. That's me.
And that one means,
"time for bed."
I like you better
as a sister than a mom.
Ouch.
[Lilo] A shooting star!
[gasps]
Oh, my gosh.
I have to make a wish.
You, out!
- What? Why? Whoa.
- Out!
You can't be here.
It won't come true.
Gravity is increasing.
- No, it's not, sister.
- Oh.
I wish a wish upon a star,
even though it's very far.
I hope and pray, hope it might
send me my wish tonight.
All I wish is a friend.
A real friend.
Someone who won't tease me.
Someone who won't run away.
Like a best friend.
[crashing, rumbling]
[whispers] Send me an angel.
The nicest one you have.
Please.
[speaking Tantalog]
[laughing]
- [toad croaking]
- Huh?
[speaking Tantalog]
- [toad croaks]
- [grunting]
[device beeping]
Huh. What does this thing do?
Give me that back! You're
not authorized to touch that.
Why? Does it eject you
from the ship? That'd be nice.
[screaming, grunting]
It's connected
to his tracking collar.
[scoffs]
That's never gonna work.
You might as well
give him a mood ring.
That collar tells us exactly
where he is at all times.
[screen beeping]
[grunts]
[gasps]
[electrical humming]
[electricity crackles]
[power cuts off]
And that's why
our mission cannot fail.
[computer] Mission failed.
Oh, no!
You know, I am right so often,
I don't even enjoy it anymore.
The novelty
has completely worn off.
[strains]
Whoo-hoo! [groans]
[♪ pop music playing,
Mark Ronson "Uptown Funk"]
[sniffing, gasps]
Mmm.
Oh, this is bad. This is bad.
Will you relax?
I know his every move.
Yeehaw! [laughing]
What the hell?
[laughs, screams]
[grunts] Hmm.
- Huh?
- [screams]
[speaking Tantalog, laughing]
[bridesmaid grunting]
- [gasps]
- [crowd clamoring]
- I saw it over there.
- Where did it go?
- Huh?
- [guest screaming]
How are we gonna find him?
We just have to follow
the path of destruction.
I got him!
- [speaking Tantalog]
- [gasps] It talked to me!
[crowd gasping]
[sniffs] Huh? Ah!
Ooh! [grunting]
[exclaims]
[Jumba] There.
Jumba! No,
you can't fly this close!
- Seat belts, please.
- Or else--
The humans will see us.
[crowd clamoring]
[belches]
You're jeopardizing
the mission.
- We can't be seen.
- I'm in charge now.
Partners are supposed
to share.
- Oh!
- [brakes squeal]
- [bus horn honking]
- [gasps]
[♪ distorted music playing,
Mark Ronson "Uptown Funk"]
- [tires screech]
- [passengers scream]
[passengers murmuring]
[♪ Hawaiian music playing]
[Pleakley]
It's called "vacation."
Once every solar year,
the human migrates
to go see a sunlight
and drink celebratory poison.
What are we doing here?
We've gotta find 626.
We will, after we blend in.
How are we gonna do that?
With these. And this.
It's a Federation-certified
cloning device.
What? Who are we gonna clone?
Ugh, this is never gonna work.
[Pleakley]
Just be cool and normal.
[Jumba scoffs]
They look like a bunch
of Slim Jims with googly eyes.
[Pleakley] No, not those two.
[Jumba] Look at their
disgusting Popsicle bodies.
Human, what a downgrade.
[Pleakley gasps]
Look at these two.
They look like best friends
just like us.
They're perfect.
[Pleakley]
I'm so sorry. Sorry. Sorry.
I'm so sorry.
Here, I will hold you up.
[device whirring]
[Pleakley] Apologies.
What a nice arm you have.
- [Pleakley grunts]
- Okay. Are you guys--
[Pleakley] And I thank you.
[Jumba] I feel like
I'm walking on chopsticks.
My legs feel a little wobbly.
[Pleakley] I know.
Don't worry. They're fine.
You watched
the video I sent you, right?
The walking video?
Yeah, but I didn't know
it was gonna be like this.
One foot
in front of the other.
[chuckles, grunting]
[both grunting]
[Pleakley] Cool and normal.
- Aloha.
- How are you?
- I'm good. Thank you.
- I would like to check in.
- Okay.
So, how many nights
will you be staying with us?
I don't want to stay with you.
I would like my own room
with a door.
Oh, and a hot tube.
I would like a hot tube.
Uh, a hot tub?
- Yes, that's how you say it...
- [chuckles]
- ...down here.
- Okay.
And where are
you visiting us from?
- Earth.
We both grew up in Earth.
Earth. Okay,
that should be about it.
Marcus, could you help him
with his bags please?
Yes.
[door closes]
What is it?
Gotta be some kind
of a dog, right?
[worker] What kind of dog
has six legs, bro?
[sighs]
Oh, nice. That went
better than I expected.
[Jumba] Which part, falling
down? It was embarrassing.
Hangers.
[Jumba] Humans.
Disgusting.
They're really
simple creatures.
Every time an asteroid hits,
they start life all over.
It's quite adorable, actually.
You know what I'd really
like to do while we're here?
Sneeze. Humans do this thing
where they blast juice
out of their nose.
What are you doing?
I'm finding him.
We only have 48 hours.
Wait! No! Wait, wait, wait.
Humans have never seen
a portal before.
The Grand Councilwoman
was very clear
not to draw attention
to ourselves!
What about that guy?
- [device beeps]
- [screams]
Listen,
I majored in Earth studies
and minored in human textiles.
- Wow!
- Trust me.
- We need to blend in.
- [elevator bell dings]
[woman] Fourth floor, please.
[Jumba] Can you stop that?
[on TV]
Aloha, I'm Stephanie Lum.
Breaking news on a
strange situation last night.
A local tour bus ran over
an unidentified wild animal
who terrorized a wedding.
The creature is recovering at
the Nā Mea Ola Animal Rescue.
- More on that at 10:00...
- Bingo.
...and hear from
the wedding photographer.
Tūtū, can I go
into the animal shelter?
Please, please, please.
Nani lets me do it.
Okay. But no wander.
I'll pick you
after I pau shopping, okay?
- Yeah!
- Hey, hey, hey, hey!
If anyone tries anything,
hit 'em in the eyes with this.
Whoa! Cool! [laughs]
Ho ho.
[Lilo laughs]
Whoa. Okay.
[groaning, gasping]
[gasps]
[speaking Tantalog]
[barks]
Uh, no, no.
[speaking Tantalog]
[groaning]
[dog whimpers]
[Lilo] Can I pet
the dogs again?
- Hi, AJ.
- Okay.
But you know you can't feed
the dogs candy again, right?
[sighs]
Lilo.
[candy rustling]
But it makes them happy.
It makes them have diarrhea.
Hmm? [sniffs]
Huh?
[gasps, speaks Tantalog]
[panting]