[gentle music playing]
[exhales deeply]
Oh. Good morning, Daniel-san.
Morning.
Welcome to Miyagi family dojo. You like?
This is really something.
Who are all these guys?
[Mr. Miyagi] All of Miyagi ancestor.
And who's that?
Ah, that is Miyagi Shimpo Sensei.
First Miyagi bring karate to Okinawa.
Like all Miyagi,
Shimpo Sensei was fisherman.
Love fishing.
Love sake.
One day, strong wind,
strong sun, strong sake,
but no fish.
Shimpo Sensei fall asleep
off coast of Okinawa,
wake up off coast of China. [chuckles]
[uplifting music playing]
[Mr. Miyagi] The Han family took him in,
taught him art of kung fu.
When Sensei return to Okinawa,
Miyagi karate was born.
Two culture, two martial art.
Two branches, one tree.
A bond that kept Hans and Miyagis
connected still today.
Whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa.
[gasps]
[suspenseful music playing]
[in Mandarin] Master Han! Master Han!
The Doctor is coming.
Stall her. Go.
Get Li!
The Doctor! Li, the Doctor!
The Doctor!
Welcome to Han Academy.
Are you looking to learn Kung Fu?
Never too late to start
even for an old woman.
We start with jacket on - jacket off.
Take off jacket, put on jacket.
I know he told you to stall me.
I did nothing of the sort.
He did ask. Sorry.
Go!
[chuckles]
Where is my son?
Tea?
[Dr. Fong] I'm not here for tea.
Where is Li?
Kung Fu is very empowering...
Uncle,
with all due respect.
I already lost one son to your "path."
I will not lose another.
I understand.
[Dr. Fong] I know what Li means to you...
but I will not have him put in harm's way.
[Mr. Han] We both agree.
If you could only see
how Kung Fu helps him -
Each time life knocked me down,
Kung Fu helped me find my way back
to the proper path.
This is for you.
What's this?
I got a new position -
- at a hospital in New York.
New York?
It's a chance to restart for both of us.
Why two hats?
So you can give one to Li...
...when he finds the courage
to come out from behind your screen.
[in English]
Xiao Li, I'll see you tonight at dinner.
[in Mandarin] Very smart.
Your mother.
[Li huffs]
W--
[pensive music playing]
Were you even going to ask me?
[in English] Oh, there you are.
I'm sorry.
Xiao Li, would you like to
move to New York?
No, Mom, our life's here.
And how long were you gonna keep this
a secret from me?
And which one of us is keeping secrets?
I was training. Not fighting.
You practice violence,
you get violence in return.
You of all people should know that.
Xiao Li, there will be so many
other things for you in New York.
Why are you speaking in English, Mom?
New city, new language.
And you can leave all this stuff here.
Hey! Can I have your gloves?
Whatever.
["Home" playing]
♪ Darling, won't you take me home? ♪
♪ Send me shivers somewhere I used to go ♪
♪ Wrap my name across your mouth ♪
♪ When I let my feelings down ♪
♪ Darling, won't you take me home? ♪
[horns honking]
♪ Yeah, won't you take me ♪
♪ Oh-oh, oh-oh-oh ♪
[bicycle bell rings]
♪ Tell me, does your mother know? ♪
♪ Like the back of my car on a sunny day ♪
♪ You're the song on the radio
I never play ♪
♪ You're the words in my soul
That I wanna say ♪
♪ That I wanna say ♪
♪ Won't you make me say? ♪
♪ Won't you take me home? ♪
♪ Send me shivers somewhere I used to go ♪
[song fades]
[sighs] The boxes arrived.
Oh. It's nice.
[sighs]
[Dr. Fong sighs]
Go check out your room.
[horns honking,
sirens blaring in distance]
-[Li] Hey, Mama.
-Hmm?
I'm gonna try to find
something for dinner, all right?
I think I saw a pizza place
around the corner.
-Well, don't go too far.
-Sure.
And be careful.
I'm always careful.
["Tick-Tick" playing]
♪ Never knew life would be a big dipper ♪
♪ Always gotta be a little bit slicker ♪
♪ Got room to improve with the groove
Gonna make the beat quicker ♪
♪ Tick-tick-ticker ♪
♪ Why have people gotta be meaner?
Make things cleaner ♪
♪ Work on demeanor
Reach for the sky, be a dreamer ♪
♪ Life'll be a little bit sweeter ♪
♪ When the day comes
When you finally meet her ♪
[entry bell rings]
Can I help you?
Uh, yeah.
Do you guys have, um,
like, a stuffed crust?
[scoffs, chuckles]
[chef] No, we don't have stuffed crust.
But you know what?
I think I can help you out.
You need to get back in your car,
drive through the Holland Tunnel
to Jersey,
go 20 miles in any direction,
find yourself a nice,
crappy little strip mall,
and I'm sure you can find a stuffed crust.
Are you guys done?
[chuckles]
Hi. I apologize on behalf of these morons.
Oh!
-One of whom is my dad.
-I'm a moron?
Um, we don't have stuffed crust.
We have plain, pepperoni,
sausage and peppers,
Grandma's, Sicilian, eggplant.
Uh. Yeah. Pepperoni. Let's do pepperoni.
Pepperoni it is. Anything else?
Toilet paper?
[diner laughing] What? Toilet paper.
Sorry.
Context: I just moved in down the street,
so I'm trying to pick up
some stuff for the apartment.
Is there a place nearby that's open?
Preferably one where I don't
have to drive an hour to Jersey,
'cause I just flew in 18 hours
from Beijing.
[chuckles]
Yeah, yeah.
There's a bodega around the corner.
-Uh...
-Convenience store.
We call them bodegas here.
Oh. Weird. Cool.
Thanks. I'll be right back.
Uh, can I get a name for the order?
Yeah. Li Fong.
Welcome to New York, Li Fong.
Thanks.
-[entry bell rings]
-What?
Since when did you get so charming?
Someone in this place needs to be.
[diner] Ouch.
Ah. School starts at 7:45 sharp.
You take the L train to--
To Union Square and then I transfer
to the Six to Canal. Yeah.
-And then you see Ms. Morgan.
-Ms. Morgan.
She's gonna give me the schedule.
I got it, Mom.
I think.
Um, how about you?
First day at the hospital. Ready?
I got it.
I think.
-Thank you.
-Yeah.
["Please" playing]
♪ I seen a lot of keys in my life, uh ♪
♪ Got people wanna please in my life, uh ♪
♪ Got varying degrees in my life, uh ♪
♪ If only I could seize
All the right stuff ♪
♪ Get rid of the disease in my life, uh ♪
♪ Oh, the birds and bees in my life, uh ♪
♪ What's the forest from the trees
In my life, uh ♪